这里是伯克
This is Berk.
它离地图太远了，几乎是一个不存在的地方
So far off the map that it might as well not exist.
那我的部落？
My village?
一句话：主打一个坚固
In a word, sturdy.
它在这里已经孕育了几代人
It's been here for generations,
但并不代表每栋建筑都很脏很旧
but every single building is new.
这里的空气清新，水质清澈，
The air is crisp, the water is clean,
当然这些都没什么好讲的
and the views are nothing to complain about.
唯独就是有暴兽
The only downsides are the pests.
你应该知道，平时大多数地方都有老鼠或蚊虫
You see, most places have mice or mosquitoes.
我们有...
We have...
龙
Dragons.
像这种情况大多数人都会仓皇而逃吧
Most people would leave.
我们却不
Not us.
因为我们是维京人
We're Vikings.
我们不会逃避战斗，而是主动发起战斗
We don't run from fights. We start them.
—嘿！希卡普！—晚上好
-Hey! Hiccup! -Evening.
快回家！
Go home!
我会马上回的，呃……
I will just as soon as I, uh...
你又挡道了！
You're in the way again!
希卡普，快装死！
Hiccup, play dead!
看到没有，龙就是
You see, dragons have been
这里最大的麻烦
a bit of a problem.
你以为一只龙，好吧，哪儿哪儿都是龙。
Here and, well, everywhere.
所以我们决定向他们开战。
So we decided to take the fight to them.
...这对我们有什么好处？
...How's that working out for us?
额...
Eh...
-哇哦！-吊毛你在这做什么？
-Whoa! -What are you doing?
这个吊毛怎么又放出来了？
What is he doing out again?
快呆在其他地方去，滚蛋
Get inside. Go on.
那人就是斯托伊克，
That's Stoick the Vast,
部落的首领
chief of the tribe.
据说，当他还是个婴儿的时候，
They say, when he was a baby,
他就把龙的头直接干了下来
he popped a dragon's head clean off its shoulders.
真的假的？
Do I believe it?
哦看样子是真的 —目前我们有什么线索没？
-Yes, I do. -What have we got?
Gronckles、Nadders、Zipplebacks、Skrills（龙的种类）
Gronckles, Nadders, Zipplebacks, Skrills.
今夜恐怕有点难熬
Snorti spotted a Monstrous Nightmare.
看见夜煞（龙）吗？
Any Night Furies?
目前还没有，酋长
None so far, Chief.
行
Good.
—跟我来 —好的，酋长
-Follow me. -Right, Chief.
来吧，你们这些可怜虫！
Come on, you wretches!
加油，干起来兄弟们儿！
You heard him. Come on, lads.
哦 又溜出来了？
Oh. Out again?
你当我不存在好吧
Just pretend I'm not even here.
我会在你叫我走之前离开的......
I'll be in and out before you can say...
没门儿
Not so fast.
求你了大哥
Come on, please.
这个呆头呆脑
The meathead with attitude
有点装B还指着我的人是Gobber
and interchangeable hands is Gobber.
拿着，走吧
Here. Go on.
我从小就是他的徒弟
I've been his apprentice
我会一直盯着你
-ever since I was little. -I'm keeping my eye on you.
我好像不能呆在这里吧
I'm not even supposed to be out here.
哈！我又没有叫你来好吧？
Ha! Since when did that ever stop you?
守卫粮食仓库
Guard the food stores.
—是的，酋长 —保护家畜
-Aye, Chief. -Protect the livestock.
遵命，斯托伊克
Aye, Stoick.
一定留意夜煞
And keep an ear out for Night Furies.
上铁锤
Hammer.
赶紧灭火！
Fire brigade!
啊，这是消防队
Ah, the fire brigade.
在伯克部落里很酷的一帮爷们儿
Berk's cool kids.
他们开始参与行动
They get to be out in the action.
伙计们，让开！
Guys, out of the way!
但他们都是噱头
But they're nothing
不够有范儿
without their captain,
不够闪耀
the shining star of our generation.
要我说的话，无需任何训练就超吊的
A-Amazing without even trying.
把所有烟都灭掉的那个人
The one that smokes them all.
阿斯特丽德
Astrid.
看什么？
What?
呃…
Uh...
你不是应该在家吗？
Shouldn't you be in bed?
快点，回去做你的事
Come on, back to work.
靠，我真的需要出来一下
You know, I need to get out there.
让我展示下，留下我的脚印
Show my stuff, make my mark.
你确实做了很多功课，但都没做对呢
You've made plenty of marks, all in the wrong places.
就给我两分钟 我要干掉一条龙
Give me two minutes. I'll-I'll take down a dragon.
我的人生才会有可能啊
My life will get infinitely better.
你信不信我还能顺带撩到一个女朋友
I might even get a girlfriend.
你身后有一只 Zippleback！
There's a Zippleback behind you!
阿斯特丽德啊？
Astrid?
但她是一位真正的维京人啊
But she's a real Viking.
你不能挥动锤子
You can't wield a hammer.
又不能挥动斧头
You can't swing an axe.
你甚至拿不会使用任何一件武器
You can't even throw one of these.
行，那我给你看这个
See, but this... this will throw it for me.
—哦，又来了 ，我重新设计它了
-Oh, another one. -It's fully redesigned.
这、这是……
It-it's...
—哇哦！—呼！
-Whoa! -Whew!
这是，呃...
It's, uh...
双管齐下，双杀看到没有
double-barreled.
好的，这就是我所说的问题
You see, this right here... this is what I'm talking about.
好吧，这只是一个轻微的校准问题
Okay, this is a mild cal... mild calibration issue.
如果你真的想出去
If you ever want to get out there
与龙战斗，你必须放弃掉这一切的幼稚......
and start fighting dragons, you've got to stop all of...all of this.
你刚才又向我做了这个手势
You just gestured to all of me.
对啊 别把自己当多厉害的家伙
Yeah. Stop being all of you.
哦...
Oh...
哦，是的
Oh, yeah.
长官，您正在开一个很大的玩笑
You, sir, are playing a dangerous game.
保持你这个态度？
Keeping this contained?
你会后悔的
There will be consequences.
好吧，感谢你给我机会让我后悔
Well, I will take my chances.
剑……给我磨 少废话
Sword... sharpen. Now.
我相信终有一天，我会证明给大家看的
One day, I'll get out there.
因为在这里杀死一条龙，你就拥有最高荣誉
Because killing a dragon is everything around here.
Gronckles很强硬
Gronckles are tough.
只要拿下一只一定会备受关注
Taking one down would at least get me noticed.
Zippleback双头龙？
A Zippleback?
真是让人刺激又兴奋.
Exotic, exciting.
两个脑袋，就是两倍的荣誉
Two heads, twice the status.
砍掉Nadder的头
Lopping off a Nadder's head
一定会向他们证明我属于这里
would definitely show them I belong.
加油，小伙子们！
Come on, lads!
他们（龙）要抓羊
They found the sheep.
那就放手一搏
Then let loose with everything we've got.
然后还有
And then there's
可怕的夜煞（龙）
the Monstrous Nightmare.
重新装载！
Reload!
只有最优秀的维京人才能追求最高荣誉
Only the best Vikings go after those.
但最终的奖品
But the ultimate prize
是一条从来没人见过的龙
is the dragon that no one has ever seen.
—我们称之为...—夜煞！
-We call it the... -Night Fury!
跳！
Jump!
狂欢之夜
And we've got a Night Fury.
从不偷食物，从不现身
Never steals food, never shows itself.
永不失手
And never misses.
是时候让老戈伯接管了
Time for old Gobber to take over.
待在这儿
Stay put here.
别乱跑，我认真的
Here. I'm serious.
从来没有人杀死过夜煞
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
开火！
Attack!
这就是为什么我要成为第一个
That's why I'm going to be the first.
—又是你？快回来！我很注意你的
-You again? Get back inside! -I'll make a point of it.
你这样会害死自己的，希卡普！
You're going to get yourself killed, Hiccup!
我知道！抱歉
I know! Sorry.
来，把那个给我
Here, give me that.
小心点！
Mind yourself!
这只Nadder仍然有攻击性
This Nadder still has some fire in it.
来吧
Come on.
给我个可以射击的东西 给我个可以射击的东西
Give me something to shoot at. Give me something to shoot at.
来吧，让我秀一波
Come on, show yourself.
我打中了
I hit it.
我打中了！
I hit it!
有人看到吗？我打中了
Did anybody see that?
你是个例外
Except for you.
噢，天哪
Oh, gods.
斯皮特洛，别让它逃走
Spitelout, do not let that escape.
OK
Thanks a lot.
你出局了
You're all out.
让我们看看你还有什么招数
Let's see what else you're made of.
是的，我就是这么想的
Aye, that's what I thought.
哦，对了还有一件事需要了解
Oh, and there's one more thing to know.
当心！
Look out!
对不起，爸爸
Sorry, Dad.
小心！
Watch out!
好的，但是我遇到了夜煞
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
爸爸，这一次和以往任何时候都不一样
Dad, this isn't like any other time.
我是说，我真的击中了一个
I mean, I really hit one.
是的，一条没人见过的龙
Aye, a dragon no one's ever seen.
因为它你利用夜煞作为功劳
Because it uses night as its camouflage.
如果你眯起眼睛，你就会看到它遮住了星星
If you squint, you can see it blotting out the stars.
—我就是这样把它击落的 —停！
-That's how I shot it down. -Stop!
停止
Stop.
每次你走出去，灾难就会发生
Every time you step outside, disaster happens.
你难道看不出来这是一个很大的问题吗
Can you not see that I have bigger problems?
冬天快到了，
Winter is almost here,
我还要养活整个村庄的人
and I have an entire village to feed.
在你我之间，这个村庄可以做到
Between you and me, the village could do
喂食量少一点
with a little less feeding.
这不是玩笑，希卡普！
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
为什么你不能遵守规则按命令作为
Why can't you follow the simplest orders?
因为我无法阻止心中的那个自己
Because I can't stop myself.
好吗？我看到一条龙，我必须……杀了它
Okay? I see a dragon, and I have to just... kill it.
你知道，这...这就是我
You know, i-it's... it's who I am.
儿子，你还有很多路要走
You are many things, son,
但屠龙者不一定是你的人生
but a dragon killer is not one of them.
回到屋子里
Get back to the house.
确保他留在那里
Make sure he stays there.
一个人能把事情搞砸到什么程度？
How much can one person mess up?
现在，很有可能其他人也会被赶出该岛
Anyone else would have been booted off the island by now.
我猜作为酋长的儿子有其特权吧
I guess being son of the chief has its privileges.
但如果不是因为酋长的话……
If not for the chief, though...
无论如何，我爸爸非常为我感到骄傲，所以......
Anyway, my dad's super proud of me, so...
爸爸，我刚才还在说……
Dad, I was just talking...
不要在公共场合跟我说话
Don't talk to me in public.
你知道吗，我确实打中了一个
You know, I really did hit one.
没错，希卡普
Of course you did, Hiccup.
他从来不听我讲
He never listens.
嗯，这是我们家的传统
Well, that runs in the family.
当他这么做的时候，
And-and when he does,
总是带着失望的表情，
it's always with some disappointed scowl,
就像有人忘记了炖菜里最重要肉食一样
like somebody forgot the meat in the stew.
我明白你的意思
I've seen that look.
喂 你想的全都错了，知道吗？
Oi. You're thinking about this all wrong, eh?
重要的不是你的外表
It's not so much what you look like.
他无法忍受的是你的内心
It's what's inside of you he can't stand.
我谢谢你~
Thank you for summing that up.
等、等一下 重点是……
W-Wait. The point is...
不要再那么努力地去成为你不该成为的人
stop trying so hard to be something you're not.
我只是想成为你们中的一员
I just want to be one of you guys.
我知道你会的
I know you do.
没有人说过这会很容易！
No one said it would be easy!
但我提醒你们一下，
But may I remind you,
我们都是最优秀的龙战士后代
we are all descendants of the finest dragon fighters
维京人所到之处，
from everywhere Vikings have traveled,
维京人聚集在这里是因为他们知道
who gathered here because they knew
距离龙的巢穴
that we were within spitting distance
很近，这很关键
of a key dragon's nest.
如果我们能拿下它，
If we can just take it,
我们就能彻底消灭魔鬼
we can wipe out the devils for good.
拿下？我们根本找不到它
Take it? We can't even find it.
没错
Exactly.
听到你说这个巢穴
This nest is starting to sound
像在编童话故事
more and more like a fairy tale.
我们都累坏了
We're exhausted.
搞得我们是需要证明什么吗，嗯？
And what do we have to show for it, eh?
无需证明！
Nothing!
我们有目标
We have purpose.
哦，又来
Oh, come on.
我们是博克岛的战士，
We are the warriors of Berk,
当太阳洒在这片土地上，我们是最顽强的部落
the roughest, toughest tribe this side of the sun.
不对吗？
No?
呸
Phlegma.
我们亲眼目睹你独自一人击倒了 Zippleback
We watched you take down a Zippleback singlehandedly.
我的意思是，你曾经战斗中确实失去了一条腿，
I mean, sure, you lost your leg in the process,
但你取得胜利了，不是吗？
but you came out on top, didn't you?
—嗯...—是的，你太棒了
-Well... -Yes, you did.
雷查，你的人民来自远东
Retcha, your people came from the Far East.
真菌兄，来自丝绸之路的您一路相伴
Fungi, yours all the way from-from the Silk Road.
Loogi，你的人来了
Loogi, your people came
来自阳光普照的布拉兰海岸
from the sun baked coasts of Bláland.
看看我们
And look at us.
我们仍在这里，我们仍一直战斗
We're still here. We're still fighting.
我们仍然互相照应
We're still watching each other's backs.
那么我们真的要收拾行李回家吗？
So are we really gonna pack up and go home
这些血腥的野兽
while these bloody beasts
仍然在威胁我们！
are still a threat to all of our lands?
这就是我们吗？
Is that who we are?
—不 —是吗？
-No. -Is it?
—不 —是吗？！
-No. -Is it?!
不！
No!
是吗？
Is it?!
不！
No!
是吗？
Is it?
呃，不，酋长，我想不是
Uh, no, Chief, I guess not.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
戈蒂长老，给我们一个信号吧
Elder Gothi, give us a sign.
我们有机会在冰形成之前找到巢穴吗？
Do we stand a chance of finding the nest before the ice sets in?
那么这就是我所需要的一切
Then that's all I need.
我们又回到了迷雾之中
Back into the fog we go.
好的，各位
All right, everyone.
准备好船只！
Prepare the ships!
我们走吧！
Let's go!
当他们烧毁我们的船时，我是否应该拿起我的水桶手
Do I take my bucket hand for when they burn our ships
或者当他们沉没时我的游泳手？
or my swimming hand for when they sink them?
别那么快，戈伯
Not so fast, Gobber.
我没有时间训练今年的新兵，
I don't have time to train this year's recruits,
所以你就会这么做
so you'll do it.
啊，古老的成年礼
Ah, the old rite of passage.
小嗝嗝刚刚成年，不是吗？
Hiccup's just come of age, hasn't he?
我指的是其他人
I meant the others.
是的，所以当我忙的时候，他会守着摊位
Yeah, so while I'm busy, he'll c-cover the stall.
熔化的钢水，锋利的刀片，
Molten steel, razor-sharp blades,
他有很多空闲时间
lots of time on his hands.
怕会出现什么问题吗？
What could possibly go wrong?
噢，我该拿他怎么办呢，戈伯？
Oh, what am I gonna do with him, Gobber?
让他坚持训练
Stick him in training.
不，我是认真的
No. I'm serious.
是的，我也是
Yeah, so am I.
这个孩子最想要的就是这个
The kid wants this more than anything.
不管你信不信，
Believe it or not,
那个年轻人实际上想让你感到骄傲
that young man actually wants to make you proud.
但他有自己的想法
But he's got a mind of his own.
从他母亲那里学的这些
Gets that from his mother.
看看她最后怎么了
Look what happened to her.
是的，因为瓦尔卡当时很固执
Yeah, 'cause Valka was the stubborn one.
你看，以前当我还是个孩子的时候...哦，又讲这些
-See, when I was a boy... -Oh, here we go.
我服从命令了 对吧？我努力了
I-I followed orders. Right? I worked hard.
因为我相信维京人能够做到一切
Because I believed in what a-a Viking could do.
粉碎山脉，
Crush mountains,
平坦的森林，平静的海洋
level forests, tame seas.
我知道我是谁，以及我必须成为什么样的人
I knew what I was and what I had to become.
我儿子希卡普……他不是那样的男孩
Hiccup is... he's not that boy.
他根本没机会追随我的脚步？
What chance does he have of following in my footsteps?
确实
Yeah.
但你无法阻止他，斯托伊克
You can't stop him, Stoick.
你只能为他做好准备
You can only prepare him.
因为事实是
Because the truth is
我们不会一直在他身边保护他
we aren't always gonna be around to protect him.
他会成长，他会再次溜出去的
He's gonna get out there again.
他现在可能已经在外面了....
He's probably out there now.
我怎么会丢掉我亲手打的龙
How could I lose an entire dragon?!
我做到了
I did it.
我做到了！
I did it!
哦，你为什么还没死？
Oh, why couldn't you have been dead?
现在我必须杀了你
Now I have to kill you.
希卡普
Hiccup.
爸爸 呃……
Dad. Uh...
爸爸，我想和你谈谈
Look, I need to talk to you, Dad.
儿子，我也需要和你谈谈
I need to speak with you, too, son.
我决定不
I've decided I don't want
-与龙战斗 -我想是时候了
-to fight dragons. -I think it's time
你学会了与龙战斗
you learn to fight dragons.
什么？
What?
嗯，你先来
Well, you go first.
不不不不不 你、你先来
No, no, no, no. You-you go first.
你的愿望实现了
You get your wish.
龙的试炼
Dragon training.
早上开始
Start in the morning.
噢，天哪，我真的应该第一个到
Oh, man, I really should've gone first.
你知道，因为我在想，
You know, 'cause I-I was thinking,
我们有很多与龙搏斗的维京人，
we have a surplus of dragon-fighting Vikings,
但是我们有足够会做面包的维京人吗？或者......
but do we have enough bread-making Vikings or...
你会需要这个
You'll need this.
爸爸……我不想和龙战斗
Dad... I don't want to fight dragons.
别装啦
Come on.
不，你很需要
Yes, you do.
不，让我重新表述一下
No, let me rephrase.
我无法杀死龙
I can't kill dragons.
但你会的
But you will.
不，我非常肯定我不会
No, I'm very extra sure that I won't.
是时候了，希卡普
It's time, Hiccup.
呃……你听不到我说话吗？
Uh... can you not hear me?
你吖听不到我说话吗？！
Can you not hear me?!
火焰试炼是维京人诞生的地方
The Trial of Flame is where Vikings are made.
这里是英雄的诞生地，这里是未来领袖的诞生地
Where heroes are forged, where future chiefs are born.
我……我不是那种人
I... I'm none of those things.
爸爸，我和你不一样
I'm not like you, Dad.
听
Listen.
当你拿着这把斧头时，
When you carry this axe,
你带着我们所有人
you carry all of us with you.
这意味着你像我们一样同行，
Which means you walk like us,
你说话像我们，你思考像我们
you talk like us, you think like us.
不再有这样的事了
No more of... this.
你刚才向我所有人做了手势
You just gestured to all of me.
成交？
Deal?
这次谈话感觉非常一边倒
This conversation is feeling very one-sided.
成交不？
Deal?
成交
Deal.
很棒
Good.
努力训练
Train hard.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
也许回吧
Probably.
我会在这里的
And I'll be here.
也许吧
Maybe.
欢迎来到火焰试炼
Welcome to the Trial of Flame.
这是我们一直在等待的时刻
The moment we've all been waiting for.
我只需要为我的雕像选择一个位置
I just got to pick a spot for my statue.
从这里看去，它要大得多
It's so much bigger from down here.
你们能相信我们真的站在这里吗？
Can you guys believe we're actually standing here?
这里是格雷比尔酋长杀死低语死神的地方
This is where Chief Greybile slew the Whispering Death.
是的，这就是酋长 Tuffnut
Yeah, and it's where Chief Tuffnut
将会消灭一切
will slay everything else.
-观察并学习 -伙计，我等不及了
-Watch and learn. -Man, I can't wait
获得一些传奇的战争创伤！
to get some legendary war wounds!
是的，就像我脸上被划了一道很深的伤口
Yeah, like a nasty gash right across my face.
—叫我无聊...—无聊
-Call me boring... -Boring.
...但我很高兴看到
...but I'm just excited to see
近距离观察一些真实的活龙
some real live dragons up close.
你知道，我可以不受永久性伤害并且......
You know, I could do without the permanent injuries and...
噢，那还有什么荣耀呢？
Oh, where's the glory in that?
是啊，只有留下疤痕才有趣
Yeah, it's only fun if you get a scar out of it.
我知道，对吧？
I know, right?
疼痛
Pain.
爱它
Love it.
哦，太好了 谁让他进来的？
Oh, great. Who let him in?
嗯，我猜爸爸一定利用了一些关系，对吧？
Mm, I guess Daddy pulled some strings, huh?
你们两个在这里是不是有点老了？
Aren't you two, like, a little old to be here?
—哎哟 —等等，你说什么，小子？
-Ouch. -Wait, what did you say, whippersnapper?
你说什么？能再说一遍吗？
What did you say? Can you say it again?
没事，这的确是一个敏感的话题
Yeah, touchy subject.
他们已经几次未能通过龙训练了
They've flunked dragon training a few times.
嗯，实际上是四次
Um, it was four times, actually.
是的，这就叫困难
Yeah, and it's called being held back.
因为它太珍贵了，不能放弃
As in too valuable to let go of.
真的很敏感，希卡普
Real sensitive, Hiccup.
顺便说一句，名字好听
Nice name, by the way.
你的名字是 Snotlout
Your name is Snotlout.
确切地说
Exactly.
这是一个很有男子气概的维京人名字
It's a manly Viking name.
从古代文献翻译为
Translates from the ancient texts as
“打掉鼻涕的人……”
"one who beateth the snot out of a..."
住口
Shut up.
让我们开始吧
Let's get started.
该死的孩子们
Bloody kids.
你们将是最新加入这一悠久传统的人
You are now the latest to join this time-honored tradition.
我们部落里出生的每一个咬脚趾的人
Every toe biter born into our tribe
总有一天要在这个竞技场生存下来
must one day survive this arena
如果他们希望与我们并肩作战
if they ever hope to do battle alongside the rest of us.
这将是艰苦的
It will be grueling.
这将非常非常危险
And it will be very, very dangerous.
但表现最好的人将赢得“顶级杀手”的称号
But whoever does best will win the title of Top Slayer.
并且随之而来的是...
And with it...
随之而来的是，他们第一次杀死龙的荣誉
And with it, the honor of killing their first dragon
当着全村人的面
in front of the entire village.
没有比这更大的荣耀
There is no greater glory.
什么？
What?
小嗝嗝已经杀死了一只夜煞，
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury,
那么，这是否会让他失去资格或者......
so does that, like, what, disqualify him or...
哦，别理他
Oh, ignore him.
你很瘦
You're skinny.
你很虚弱
You're weak.
这会让你不那么容易成为目标
That'll make you less of a target.
他们会认为你的收获微乎其微
They'll see you as slim pickings.
不值得付出努力
Not worth the effort.
他们会追求更多，呃……
They'll go after the more, uh...
而是像维京人一样的青少年
Viking-like teens instead.
这些门后面只是众多野兽中的一小部分
Behind these doors are just a few of the many species
你将学会战斗
you will learn to fight.
致命纳德
The Deadly Nadder.
攻击8，护甲16
Attack eight, armor 16.
丑陋的 Zippleback
The Hideous Zippleback.
加上 11 隐身，乘以 2
Plus 11 stealth, times two.
可怕的噩梦
The Monstrous Nightmare.
-火力 15 -可怕的恐怖
-Firepower 15. -The Terrible Terror.
—攻击八，毒液十二！—你能停下来吗！
-Attack eight, venom 12! -Will you stop that!
你这个大毛线包
You big bag of wool.
最后，是可怕的格伦克尔
And finally, the gruesome Gronckle.
下颌力量八
Jaw strength eight.
呃，嘿，大个子，你难道不
Uh, hey, big guy, aren't you gonna, like,
先教我们一些东西？
teach us something first?
我相信在实践中学习
I believe in learning on the job.
今天的主题是防守
Today is all about defense.
如果你被击中，你就出局了
If you get blasted, you're out.
或者，你懂的，挂掉
Or, you know, dead.
那么你需要的第一件武器是什么？
So what's the first thing you're gonna need?
-盾牌！-盾牌，是的 去吧
-A shield! -Shield, yes. Go.
—别挡我的路 —那是我的！
-Out of my way. -That one's mine!
盾牌是你最重要的装备
Shield is your most important piece of equipment.
如果您必须在武器和盾牌之间做出选择……
If you have to choose between a weapon and a shield...
就把它放下
Just put it down.
拿起盾牌
Take the shield.
—给它！—我的，我的，我的！
-Give it! -Mine, mine, mine!
找到你自己的盾牌！
Find your own shield!
拉夫纳特，特夫纳特，你出局了
Ruffnut, Tuffnut, you're out.
盾牌还有另一个好处：隔音
Shields are good for another thing: noise.
制造足够的机会来摆脱龙的瞄准
Make plenty of it to throw off the dragon's aim.
请记住，所有龙的爆发次数都是有限的
Remember, all dragons have a limited number of blasts.
格伦克尔 (Gronckle) 有多少个？
How many does a Gronckle have?
哦哦！六！
Ooh, ooh! Six!
是的，六个
Six, yes.
你们每个人都有一份
That's one for each of you.
不过，有趣的是，
Although, interesting tidbit,
不同地区的岩石的矿物成分各有不同...
rocks from different regions vary in mineral comp...
你在做什么...你在做什么？
What are you do... What are you doing?
你在干嘛？快进来！
What are you doing? Get in there!
鱼腿子，你出局了
Fishlegs, you're out.
—还剩四枪 —是的
-Four shots left. -Yeah.
我俩几乎会成为全场的焦点
We're pretty much gonna be the stars of this thing.
就好像我们注定要在一起一样
Almost like we were meant to be together.
这是一场淘汰赛，天才
It's an elimination game, genius.
顶级杀手只有一个
There's only one Top Slayer.
鼻涕粗，你完了
Snotlout, you're done.
三枪
Three shots.
看起来就只有你和我了，是吧？
Looks like it's just you and me, huh?
不 是只有我
Nope. Just me.
嘿！看着我！
Hey! Eyes on me!
是的 干得好，阿斯特丽德
Yes. Well done, Astrid.
还剩两枪
Two shots left.
哦，来吧
Oh, come on.
希卡普，你出局了
Hiccup, you're out.
—还剩一枪 —嘿，小心点！
-One shot left. -Hey, watch it!
呃呃！
Hiccup!
课程结束
End of lesson.
回床上去吧，你这根长得肥大的香肠
Back to bed, you overgrown sausage.
记住，龙永远、永远……
Remember, a dragon will always, always...
...去杀戮
...go for the kill.
那么，你为什么不这么做呢？
So, why didn't you?
好的
Okay.
呵呵
Huh.
我们来回顾一下，好吗？
Let's review, shall we?
阿斯特丽德今天在拳击场上哪里出了问题？
Where did Astrid go wrong in the ring today?
我翻筋斗跳水的时机不对
I mistimed my somersault dive.
太草率了，它打乱了我的反向翻滚动作
It was sloppy. It threw off my reverse tumble.
-呃，是的 我们注意到了 -嘿
-Uh, yeah. We noticed. -Hey.
退后，娘炮 好吗？
Back off my girl. All right?
—她正在尽力 —是的
-She's trying her best. -Yeah.
别责怪自己 你会成功的
Don't beat yourself up. You'll get it.
下次只要按照我的指示做就可以了
Just follow my lead next time.
阿斯特丽德是对的
Astrid's right.
你们必须对自己严厉一点
You've got to be tough on yourselves.
只需要一个薄弱环节
All it takes is one weak link.
那么你成功了？
You made it, then?
你必须开始认真对待这件事，
You got to start taking this seriously,
因为我们生活在战场上
because we are living in a battleground.
如果你还没有注意到，另一方正在获胜
And in case you haven't noticed, the other side is winning.
您将需要利用一切可能的优势
You're gonna need every advantage you can get.
所以，如果你还没有完成作业，
So, if you haven't done your homework,
请允许我向您介绍...
allow me to present to you...
……《龙之书》
...the Book of Dragons.
我们对每条龙的了解都以此为基础
Everything we know about every dragon we know of.
你们每个部落都带来了他们的智慧
Each of your tribes brought their wisdom
并体验这些页面
and experience to these pages.
这是我们最神圣的财产
It's our most hallowed possession.
今晚没有龙袭击，所以要好好学习
No dragon raids tonight, so study up.
你的意思是读吗？
You mean read?
我已经读过一百遍了
I've read it like a hundred times.
有一个大锅，可以将沸水喷到您的脸上
There's a Scauldron that sprays your face with boiling water.
然后还有，嗯，另一个...
And then there's, um, another...
我为什么要读文字
Why would I read words
当我可以杀死那些东西时，文字可以吗？
when I can just kill the stuff the words tell me stuff about?
对吧？我是说，我就是那种
Right? I mean, like, I'm the kind of guy
其他人写了关于它的文字书
that other guys write word books about.
好的
Nice.
—孩子们！—不过别担心
-Boys! -Don't worry, though.
我来这里是为了解答您所有与龙有关的疑问，好吗？
I'm here for all of your dragon-related inquiries, okay?
理论、统计数据
Theories, stats.
我甚至制作了卡片，嗯......
I've even made, um, cards, um...
你可以问我任何事情
You can ask me anything.
—别再跟着我 —给你
-Stop following me. -Here.
现在怎么样？现在就试试吧
How about now? Try me now.
绝对不是
Absolutely not.
所以...
So...
听起来很可怕，很恐怖，但很美好，不是吗？
sounds like a gruesome, grisly, good time, huh?
阅读它
Read it.
你知道，呃……
Y-You know, uh...
也许他们并不像我们想象的那么糟糕
maybe they're not as bad as we think they are.
你真的疯了吗，还是你只是表现得像那样？
Are you actually insane, or do you just act that way?
有没有...有第三种选择吗？
Is-is there... is there a third option?
我们来这里就是为了消灭龙
Wiping out dragons is why we're here.
这就是我们部落最优秀的人才聚集在一起的原因
It's why the best of our tribes came together.
因为龙确实和我们想象中的邪恶是一样的
Because yes, dragons are as bad as we think.
是的，我知道 我只是说，
Y-Yeah, I-I know. I'm just saying,
也许我们就是问题的一部分
maybe we're part of the problem.
你知道，侵入他们的土地，吃他们的食物
You know, moving in on their lands, eating their food.
哇
Wow.
你生活在不同的世界，不是吗？
You live in a different world, don't you?
什么？
What?
只是顺其自然，认为一切都是理所当然的
Just coast by, taking it all for granted.
嗯，我不这么认为...
Well, I don't think that...
无需为任何事努力，
Never having to work for anything,
无需费力站起来
never struggling to get a foot up.
好吧，猜猜怎么着
Well, guess what.
我来自虚无
I come from nothing.
父亲不需要首领，不需要施舍，不需要借口
No chief for a dad, no handouts, no excuses.
我不怕辛苦
I'm not afraid of hard work.
我愿意尽一切努力完成这项工作，
I'm willing to do whatever it takes to get the job done,
在这种情况下，这意味着消灭龙
which, in this case, means wiping out the dragons
为了大家的利益
for the good of everyone.
是的
Yeah.
你还知道什么吗？
You know what else?
我、我害怕...不敢问
I'm-I'm afraid... afraid to ask.
我看中了你的那栋大房子
I've got my eye on that big house of yours.
有一天我会成为酋长
I'm gonna be chief one day.
我对此毫不怀疑
I-I don't doubt it.
事实上，我认为我爸爸会很高兴
Actually, I think my dad would be thrilled.
再说，你也是他一直希望的孩子
Besides, you're the kid he always hoped for.
相反，他得到了……
Instead, he got...
这一切
all this.
别挡我的路，希卡普
Stay out of my way, Hiccup.
“龙的分类 ”
"Dragon classifications."
“打击级 恐惧级 神秘级 ”
"Strike class. Fear class. Mystery class."
“雷鼓
"Thunderdrum.
“当受到惊吓时，雷鼓会发出震荡的声音
"When startled, the Thunderdrum produces a concussive sound
“它可以近距离杀死一个人
"that can kill a man at close range.
“极其危险 见者必杀 ”
"Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
“伐木者
"Timberjack.
“Skrill 死亡低语 ”
"Skrill. Whispering Death.
“焚烧受害者 埋葬受害者
"Burns its victims. Buries its victims.
“扼住受害者的脖子 将受害者翻过来
"Chokes its victims. Turns its victims inside out.
“极其危险 极其危险
"Extremely dangerous. Extremely dangerous.
“见人就杀 见人就杀 见人就杀
"Kill on sight. Kill on sight. Kill on sight.
“夜煞
"Night Fury.
未知 未知
unknown. unknown.
“闪电和死亡本身的邪恶后代
"The unholy offspring of lightning and death itself.
永远不要与这条龙交战 ”
Never engage this dragon."
我几乎可以闻到它们的味道
I can almost smell them.
带我们进入海姆冥界之门
Take us in to Helheim's Gate.
又来了
Here we go again.
向左掌舵！
Hard to port!
拨起桨！卷起船帆！
Set the oars! Furl the sails!
全部一起
All together.
快点
Come on.
高一点
Higher.
我们并不孤单！
We're not alone!
—抬头看！—小心你的头！
-Look up! -Watch your heads!
折回！
Turn back!
它们无处不在！
They're everywhere!
嘿，我只是，呃……我刚好注意到
Hey, I just, uh... I just happened to notice
这本书没有提到夜煞
that the book had nothing on Night Furies.
还有其他书吗？
Is there maybe, like, like, another book?
也许，就像《夜煞》小册子……
Maybe, like, a Night Fury pamph...
集中注意力，希卡普
Focus, Hiccup.
你甚至都没尝试过
You're not even trying.
今天是关于进攻的
Today is about attack.
纳德行动敏捷，脚步轻盈
Nadders are quick and light on their feet.
你的工作就是要更快、更轻盈
Your job is to be quicker and lighter.
对不起
Sorry.
我真的开始质疑你的教学方法了！
I'm really beginning to question your teaching methods!
寻找它的盲点
Look for its blind spot.
每条龙都有一个
Every dragon has one.
找到它，藏在里面，然后攻击
Find it, hide in it, then strike.
你洗过澡吗？
Do you ever bathe?
如果你不喜欢，那就去找你自己的盲点 走吧！
If you don't like it, go find your own blind spot. Go!
是的，存在盲点
Blind spot, yes.
聋点，不是很多
Deaf spot, not so much.
我受伤了 很多伤
I am hurt. I am very much hurt.
那么，怎样才能偷偷接近夜煞呢？
So, how does one sneak up on a Night Fury?
没有人见过这样的人并能活着讲述这个故事
No one has ever met one and lived to tell the tale.
—现在，进去吧！—是的，我知道
-Now, get in there! -Yeah, I-I know.
我只是说，
I-I'm just saying, like,
—怎么会...—打嗝
-how would... -Hiccup.
向下
Down.
哇，救救你自己吧！
Whoa, save yourself!
我会处理好这件事的
I'll take care of this.
哦
Oh.
这不是我的错，阿斯特丽德
Not my fault, Astrid.
你眼中的光芒让我分心
I got distracted by the light in your eyes.
等一下！让我……
Wait! Just let me...
是的 干得好，阿斯特丽德
Yes. Well done, Astrid.
没有什么比这更好的了
Nothing like giving them
自食其果，是吧？
a taste of their own medicine, eh?
还有“干得好，鼻涕粗”，
Also, "Well done, Snotlout",
“助攻”对吧？真是个好团队！
"with the assist," right? What a team!
有人认真对待此事吗？！
Is anyone taking this seriously?!
认真对待
Take it seriously.
因为如果你忘了，我们父母的战争
'Cause in case you forgot, our parents' war
即将成为我们的！
is about to become ours!
弄清楚你站在哪一边
Figure out which side you're on.
嗯？咦？
Hmm? Huh?
呵呵，没牙
Huh. Toothless.
我敢发誓你已经……
I could've sworn you had...
...牙齿
...teeth.
- 我-没有了
- I - don't have any more.
谢谢？
Thanks?
哦，得了吧 你在开玩笑吧？
Oh, come on. You're kidding, right?
嗯
Mmm.
唔？
Hmm?
然后他转身抓住我的胳膊，
And then he turned and grabbed me arm,
并且有一个转折，
and with one twist,
他把我的手全部拿下来并整个吞了下去
he took my hand clean off and he swallowed it whole.
是的，他肯定已经把这个消息传开了，
Yeah, he must have spread the word around,
因为不到一个月，另一个人就夺走了我的腿
'cause within a month, another one had taken my leg.
可能是 Skrill
Probably a Skrill.
锯齿状牙齿，颌骨强度17
Serrated teeth, jaw strength 17.
我要为你掉落的肢体报仇，大个子
I'll avenge your fallen limbs, big guy.
我要砍掉你的手和脚
I'll chop off the hands and feet
——我所见到的每一条龙 ——不
-of every dragon that I see. -Nah.
你想要的是翅膀和尾巴
It's the wings and the tail you want.
如果它们不能飞，它们就无法逃脱
If they can't fly, they can't get away.
倒下的龙就是死龙
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
任何人都可以不依赖其他部分而生存下去
Anyone can get by without the other bits.
我将失去我的所有肢体
I'm gonna lose all of my limbs.
我自愿让拉夫纳特失去至少一条肢体
I volunteer Ruffnut to lose at least one limb.
咦？
Huh?
什么？
What?
我们是双胞胎 你的痛苦就是我的痛苦
We're twins. Your pain is my pain.
你们是双胞胎吗？
You're twins?
甚至连我们的母亲都无法区分我们
Even our own mother can't tell us apart.
这太不可思议了
It's uncanny.
好了
There we go.
阿斯特丽德的想法是正确的
Astrid's got the right idea.
尽可能睡个好觉
Get your sleep while you can.
很快，斯托伊克就会回来
Soon, Stoick will be back.
你们之中的一个人将被选中去杀死那条龙
And one of you will be chosen to kill the dragon.
WHO？
Who?
无牙！
Toothless!
早餐来啦
Brought breakfast.
嗯？哥们，你觉得怎么样？
Huh? What do you think, bud?
好的
Okay.
我搞到了一些鳕鱼……
We got some cod...
...一些鲑鱼
...some salmon
还有一整条熏鳗鱼
and a whole smoked eel.
哇啊啊啊啊啊……
Whoa, uh, uh, uh...
没有鳗鱼！不抓鳗鱼！
No eel! Scratch the eel!
是的，呃，我也不能说我喜欢它
Yeah, I, uh, can't say I love it, either.
就是这样
That's it.
坚持做好事
Stick to the good stuff.
我马上就回来，
I'll just be back here,
做好我自己的事
minding my own business.
好的
Okay.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
呼 好吧 还不错
Whew. Okay. Not bad.
它应该能起到作用
It could work.
如果……哇哦！好吧！
If it's... Whoa! Okay!
无牙！不行！天哪！
Toothless, no! Oh, gods!
无牙！
Toothless!
噢，天哪！
Oh, gods!
起作用了！
It's working!
耶！呼！
Yeah! Whoo!
今天的主题是团队合作
Today is all about teamwork.
如果你们齐心协力，你们也许就能生存下来
If you work together, you might just survive.
你看，湿了的龙头是点不着火的
You see, a wet dragon head cannot light its fire.
但 Hideous Zippleback 则更加棘手，
But a Hideous Zippleback is extra tricky,
因为一个头吸入气体，另一个头点燃气体
'cause one head breathes gas and the other head lights it.
你的工作就是知道哪个是哪个
Your job is to know which is which.
祝你好运
Good luck.
锋利的毒牙可注入毒液进行消化
Razor-sharp fangs that inject venom for predigestion.
— 更喜欢保留它的受害者... — 嘘！
-Prefers to keep its victims... -Shh!
...有意识的
...conscious.
你知道，我很高兴我们能够成为合作伙伴
You know, I'm kind of glad we got partnered.
我们女孩必须团结在一起
Us girls got to stick together.
—直到我不得不带你出去 —嘘
-Until I have to take you out. -Shush.
我想我已经基本赢得了阿斯特丽德的青睐
I think I've pretty much won Astrid over.
我的意思是，她几乎都不敢看我一眼
I mean, she can barely even look at me.
看来你找对人了
You came to the right man for advice.
-我没有问... -如果有一件事
-I didn't ask... -If there's one thing
维京女孩的大脑无法抗拒，这是......
the Viking girl brain can't resist, it's...
当心！
Look out!
—嘿！—是我们，天才
-Hey! -It's us, geniuses.
闪电般的反应
Lightning reflexes.
我看到丑陋的头颅，我就攻击
I see hideous heads, I strike.
哎哟
Ow.
哇哦
Whoa.
呃，做一个丑陋的头，阿斯特丽德
Uh, make that one hideous head, Astrid.
拯救你们自己！
Save yourselves!
也以玩弄受害者而闻名
Also known to toy with its victims,
把他们肢解成碎片
dismembering them limb from limb.
你能停止这样做吗？
Will you please stop that?
鱼腿！
Fishlegs!
搞错了
Wrong head.
快离开那里，希卡普！
Get out of there, Hiccup!
哦，来吧
Oh, come on.
是啊 后退！
Yeah. Back!
快跑……呃呃
Run... Hiccup.
别让我再告诉你！是的
Don't make me tell you again! Yeah.
嗯，没错 回到你的笔里
Yeah, that's right. Back in your pen.
现在，想一想你做了什么
Now, think about what you've done.
那么，我们今天完成了吗？
So, are we done today?
因为今天我还有一些事情需要做，呃……
J-Just because I have some things I need to, uh...
是的，我要...明天去见你们
Yeah, I'm gonna... I'm gonna see you guys tomorrow.
咦？
Huh?
嘿
Hey.
哦，来吧
Oh, come on.
尝试一下吧
Just try it.
哇哦！
Whoa!
噢，我要死了！
Oh, I'm gonna die!
哇哦，哇哦，不！
Whoa, whoa, no!
不，求你了！
No, please!
只需调整一下自己的角度
Just kind of angle yourself.
哇哦！
Whoa!
哇哦，哇哦，不！
Whoa, whoa, no!
噢，来吧！
Oh, come on!
—让开！—走开！
-Out of my way. -Move!
动起来，动起来，动起来，动起来，动起来！
Move, move, move, move, move, move!
小心点，进入它的盲点
Watch yourselves. Get in its blind spot.
我拿到了！这是我的！
I got it! It's mine!
不，别把它带过来！
No, don't bring it over here!
呃，小家伙 他叫什么名字？
Uh, little guy. What is his name again?
-我不记得了 -嘿，慢点
-I don't remember. -Hey. Slow down.
—你是想让我们出丑吗？—不，不是
-Are you trying to show us up? -N-No.
我从未见过有人能如此打败 Gronckle
I've never seen someone take down a Gronckle like that.
我的意思是，我一直都这样做，但你是如何学会的呢？
I mean, I do it all the time, but how did you learn?
学什么？具体是什么？
Learn what? What exactly was that?
好的，明白了，我很乐意解释一下
Okay, see, I-I'd love to explain.
只是，我把我的斧头留在了拳击场里
It's just, I left my axe back in-in the ring.
谁是好孩子？谁是好孩子？
Who's a good boy? Who's a good boy?
哇哦，好的
Whoa, okay.
是啊，是啊？你痒吗？
Yeah, yeah? You itchy?
是那个地方吗？
Is that the spot?
呃呃
Hiccup.
哟，他在那里
Yo, there he is.
嘿，希卡普
Hey, Hiccup.
-好的 -呃呃 WW-等一下
-Okay. -Hiccup. W-W-Wait.
-我有一个合适的问题 -所以我在想......
-I have a proper question. -So I'm thinking that...
所需要的只是你和我站在拳击场上
All it needs to be is you and me in the ring.
可怕的恐怖！
A Terrible Terror!
它和我的一样大...
It's like the size of my...
把它拿下来！
Get it off!
拿开！拿开！
Get it off! Get it off!
哎哟
Ow.
其他船只呢？
And the other ships?
爸爸！
Dad!
我来拿
I got it.
我很想念你
I missed you.
就像是，以一种超级男子气概
In, like, a super manly way.
我有很多关于火焰试炼的事情要告诉你
I got so much to tell you about the Trial of Flame.
基本上是...爸爸？
It's basically between... Dad?
爸爸？
Dad?
爸...
Da...
好的，我回家等你
Okay, I'll see you at home.
那么，没有巢穴吗？
So, no nest, then?
差远了
Not even close.
我希望你能取得更大的成功
I hope you had more success.
好吧，如果成功的话，
Well, if by success,
你的意思是你的育儿烦恼已经结束了，
you mean your parenting troubles are over,
那么，嗯，是的
then, uh, yeah.
酋长，您听到这个消息了吗？
Did you hear the news, Chief?
—大家都松了一口气 —老希卡普终于走了
-Everyone is so relieved. -Good riddance to old Hiccup.
机会
Aye.
没有人会忽视这种麻烦
No one will miss that nuisance.
希卡普...
Hiccup is...
走出去了吗？
gone?
是的
Yeah.
是的，大多数下午都是这样，但谁能责怪他呢？
Yeah, most afternoons, but who can blame him?
名人的生活可能会非常艰难
The life of a celebrity can be very rough.
他几乎无法穿过村庄
He can barely walk through the village
而不会被他的大批新粉丝包围
without being swarmed by his army of new fans.
谁能想到他有这个……
Who would've thought he has this...
和野兽相处的方式？
way with the beasts?
好的，伙计
All right, bud.
我们会慢慢来
We're gonna take this nice and slow.
开始了
Here we go.
位置三
Position three.
呃，不，四个
Uh, no, four.
你准备好了吗？
You ready?
来吧，来吧
Come on. Come on.
是啊，看看我们！
Yeah, look at us!
哇哦！
Whoa!
我的错 我的错
My fault. My fault.
是的，是的，我正在做
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
位置五
Position five.
来吧，伙计
Come on, bud.
是啊 加油，宝贝！
Yeah. Go, baby!
噢，这太神奇了！
Oh, this is amazing!
我心中的风...
The wind in my...
图纸！停！
Cheat sheet! Stop!
噢，天哪！
Oh, gods!
是的！
Yeah!
儿子！
Son!
爸爸！呃，你回来了
Dad! Uh, you're back.
呃，呃，哦...好吧，呃，Gobber 不在这里，
Uh, uh, oh... Okay, uh, Gobber's not here,
—所以，嗯...—我知道
-so, um... -I know.
来找你了
Came looking for you.
你你你做了什么？呃，为什么？
You-you-you did? Uh, wh-why?
你一直在保守秘密
You've been keeping secrets.
我有？
I have?
你以为你能瞒我多久？
Just how long did you think you could hide it from me?
我甚至不知道你在说什么……
I-I don't even know what you're talking...
这个岛上发生的任何事我都听说过
Nothing happens on this island without me hearing about it.
那么，我们来谈谈那条龙
So, let's talk about that dragon.
噢，天哪，爸爸
Oh, gods, Dad.
我-我-我真的很抱歉
I'm-I'm-I'm so sorry.
我早就该告诉你了
I-I was gonna tell you sooner.
— 我—只是不知道……
- I - just didn't know...
你不生气吗？
You're not upset?
啥？啥？
What? What?
我本来希望如此
I was hoping for this.
— 是吗？— 哦，是的
-You were? -Oh, yes.
相信我，情况只会变得更好
And believe me, it only gets better.
等你溢出来
Just wait till you spill
第一次感受到纳德的胆量
a Nadder's guts for the first time.
或者，或者将你的第一个 Gronckle 头颅安装在长矛上
Or-or mount your first Gronckle head on a spear.
多么奇妙的感觉啊
What a feeling.
儿子，你确实让我去了那里
You really had me going there, son.
那些年最糟糕的维京人
All those years of the worst Viking
伯克郡人所见过的
Berk has ever seen.
奥丁，这很艰难
Odin, it was rough.
我几乎已经放弃你了
I almost gave up on you.
而一直以来，你都对我有所隐瞒
And all the while, you were holding out on me.
全能的雷神
Thor almighty.
谁会想到龙训练
Who would have thought that dragon training
本来就是你大放异彩的地方，是吧？
would have been your place to shine, huh?
啊，你甚至可能赢得“顶级杀手”称号
Ah, you might even win Top Slayer.
就像你老爸一样
Just like your old man.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
你知道...
You know...
你在拳击场上表现得如此出色……
With you doing so well in the ring...
我要…我要…
I'm gonna... I'm gonna...
—坐下 —好的
-Sit. -Okay.
我们终于有话可谈了
We finally have something to talk about.
所以，我……
So, I...
哦！哦，我，呃……
Oh! Oh, I, uh...
我给你带了一些东西……
I brought you something...
为了……为了，呃……
To... to, uh...
保证你在拳击场内的安全
keep you safe in the ring.
你的母亲一定希望你拥有它
Your mother would have wanted you to have it.
哇哦 呃，谢谢
W-Wow. Uh, thanks.
这是她胸甲的一半
It's half of her breastplate.
配套
Matching set.
让她...
Keeps her...
它让她靠近你，你知道吗？
It keeps her close, you know?
儿子，自豪地穿上它
Wear it proudly, son.
你已经履行了你的承诺
You've held up your end of the deal.
是的
Yeah.
-是啊 累了 -是啊，我要……
-Yeah. Tired. -Yeah, I'm gonna...
—我要去睡觉了 —呃，聊得不错
-I'm gonna get some s-sleep. -Uh, good talk.
—明天是个重要的日子 —是的
-Big day tomorrow. -Yeah.
火焰试炼，它会消耗你很多的精力
The Trial of Flame, and it takes a lot out of you.
是的，火焰试炼……火焰
Yeah, Trial of Flames... Flame.
—祝你好运 —好的，谢谢你，谢谢你
-Good luck with that. -Yeah, thank you, thank you
—呃……胸帽 —我希望你喜欢……
-for the, uh... the breast hat. -I hope you like the...
—帽子 是的 —是的
-Hat. Yeah. -Yeah.
好的，那么...晚安
Okay, well... good night.
别再耍你的花招了
No more of your tricks.
-我今天要参加“Top Slayer”考试 -是的，是的，好的
-I'm taking Top Slayer today. -Yeah, yeah, okay.
这、这都是你的了 Top-Top 尽情杀戮吧
It's-it's all yours. Top-Top Slay away.
对不起
Sorry.
最后一次机会 好好把握
Last chance. Make it count.
快点！
Come on!
-加油，阿斯特丽德！你成功了！-加油，希卡普！
-Go on, Astrid! You got it! -Come on, Hiccup!
—继续！—来吧！
-Go on! -Come on!
不！
No!
半巨魔的儿子，吃老鼠……
Son of a half-troll, rat-eating...
很高兴看到她能优雅地处理这件事
Glad to see she's handling it gracefully.
你！
You!
嗯，好的
Uh, okay.
—稍后 —嘿，嘿 别那么急
-Later. -Hey, hey. Not so fast.
—安静点 —不，我不能
-Quiet down. -No, I can't.
—我要迟到了，呃...—什么？
-I'm gonna be late for, uh... -What?
到底因为什么事迟到？
Late for what, exactly?
—再过一年……—闭嘴
-Another year... -Shut up.
...以及另一场火焰试炼
...and another Trial of Flame
已经结束了
has come to an end.
戈蒂长老已经做出了决定
Elder Gothi has made her decision.
新的 Top Slayer 将是...
The new Top Slayer will be...
你成功了，希卡普
You've done it, Hiccup.
你赢得了火焰试炼
You won the Trial of Flame.
你要杀死那条龙
You get to kill the dragon.
那是我的儿子！
That's my boy!
希卡普，你赢了！
Hiccup, you won!
哇！是啊
Whoa! Yeah.
我太高兴了
Hooray me.
我等不及了……
I can't wait to...
打败它并且永不回来
Beat it and never come back.
好了，伙计 时间到了
All right, bud. Time's up.
我的想法完全一样
My thoughts exactly.
你、你到底在干什么，呃……
Wh-What are you, uh...
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
—寻找答案 —嗯？
-Looking for answers. -Huh?
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
巴德是谁？你的教练？
Who's Bud? Your trainer?
他给你穿这身衣服了吗？
Did he dress you up in this?
呃，我知道这看起来很可疑，
Uh, I-I know this looks suspicious,
但有趣的是，我，呃......
but f-funnily enough, I, uh...
呃，你说得对！你说得对 我，呃……
Uh, you're right! You're right. I, uh...
我不再说谎了
I'm through with the lies.
我一直在做服装，所以，嗯，你明白我的意思了
I've been making outfits, so, um, you got me.
是时候让每个人都知道了
It's time everybody knew.
带我回去就好
Just take me back.
哎哟！
Ow!
你为什么要这么做？
Why would you do that?
这都是谎言
That's for the lies.
其他一切都如此
And that's for everything else.
哦，不
Oh, no.
快跑！快跑！
Run. Run!
不不不
No! No.
—什么... —无牙仔，不！
-What... -Toothless, no!
停下来，没关系
Stop. It's okay.
她是我的朋友，她是我的朋友
She's a friend. She's a friend.
无牙仔，阿斯特丽德 阿斯特丽德，无牙仔
Toothless, Astrid. Astrid, Toothless.
那个，呃......夜煞
The, uh... the Night Fury.
我不会
I wouldn't.
我们死了
We're dead.
嘿 你想去哪儿？
Hey. Where do you think you're going?
希卡普！放我下来！
Hiccup! Get me down from here!
你得给我一个解释的机会
You have to give me a chance to explain.
我不听你说什么
I'm not listening to anything you have to say.
那我就不说话了
Then I won't speak.
让我们向您展示一下
Just let us show you.
请吧，阿斯特丽德
Please, Astrid.
这是什么？
What is this?
呃，这是我的设计
Uh, it's my design.
是的 差不多就是副队长
Yeah. Pretty much the cocaptain.
那么我们就把这件事了结吧
Then let's get this over with.
你明白了
You got it.
无牙仔，我们把她打倒吧
Toothless, let's take her down.
轻轻地
Gently.
没什么可害怕的
Nothing to be afraid of.
噢，感觉真好！
Oh, nice touch!
我以为你是他的副队长！
I thought you were his cocaptain!
是的！这只是龙暂时故障！
I am! It's a temporary dragon malfunction!
我们制定了整个系统，记得吗？
We worked out a whole system, remember?
如果我们活下来，我就要杀了你！
If we survive, I'm gonna kill you!
现在开始旋转
And now the spinning.
谢谢你，你这个没用的爬虫
Thank you for nothing, you useless reptile.
请让它停止
Please just make it stop.
显然我不是掌控一切的人
I'm clearly not the one in control.
那我就抱歉了！
Then I'm sorry!
无牙仔，对不起！
Toothless, I'm sorry!
美好的
Fine.
你说得很清楚
You made your point.
这并不能改变你明天必须杀死一个人的事实
It doesn't change the fact you have to kill one tomorrow.
但如果我们能改变你的想法……
But if we can change your mind...
什么？
What?
你要带大家去进行一次神奇的旅程吗？
You gonna take everyone up for a magical ride?
这并不能抹去他们对我们所做的一切，希卡普
It won't erase what they've done to us, Hiccup.
它们捕猎我们，偷走我们的食物
They hunt us, steal our food.
其中一个人带走了我妈妈
And one of them took my mom.
但我们就只能继续互相残杀吗？
But do we just keep killing one another?
相对于...？
As opposed to...?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
但是你搞砸了我们的逃跑计划，所以我需要一点时间
But you botched our escape plan, so I'm gonna need a minute.
好吧，我可能不会告发你
Well, I might not snitch on you.
我们也许不会把你扔进海里
And we might not drop you in the sea.
巴德？怎么了？
Bud? What's up?
它是什么？
What is it?
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
下来！
Get down!
无牙仔，带我们离开这里
Toothless, get us out of here.
看起来他们正在拖运猎物
It looks like they're hauling in their kill.
那我们又是什么呢？
Then what does that make us?
龙巢
The dragons' nest.
噢，我爸爸愿意付出一切来找到这个
Oh, what my dad wouldn't give to find this.
那是什么？
What is that?
好了，伙计，该走了
All right, bud, time to go.
我不敢相信花了这么长时间才弄明白
I can't believe it took this long to figure it out.
现在一切都说得通了
It all makes sense now.
它就像一个巨大的蜂巢
It's like a giant beehive.
它们是工人，那是它们的女王
They're the workers, and that's their queen.
他们的阿尔法
Their alpha.
它控制着它们
It controls them.
我们得找到你的爸爸
We got to find your dad.
不，不，不，还没有
No, no, no, not yet.
他们会……他们会杀死无牙仔
They'll... they'll kill Toothless.
阿斯特丽德，我们必须仔细考虑一下这件事
Astrid, we have to think this through carefully.
希卡普，我们刚刚发现了龙巢，
Hiccup, we just discovered the dragons' nest,
你想保守这个秘密吗？
and you want to keep it a secret?
为了保护你的宠物龙？
To protect your pet dragon?
你是认真的？
Are you serious?
是的
Yes.
好的
Okay.
那么...我们该怎么办？
Then... what do we do?
到明天为止
Just give me until tomorrow.
我会想办法的
I'll figure it out.
那是绑架我
That's for kidnapping me.
嘿，你要...
Hey, are you gonna...
其他一切都如此
And that's for everything else.
什么？
What?
好吧，我终于可以再次在公众面前露面了
Well, I can finally show my face in public again.
好的
All right.
如果有人在短短几周内告诉我，
If someone had told me that in a few short weeks,
希卡普 (Hiccup) 就不再是希卡普了……
Hiccup would've gone from being, well, Hiccup...
...在火焰试炼中获得第一名，
...to placing first in the Trial of Flame,
我的意思是，我会把它们绑在桅杆上
I mean, I would've tied them to a mast
并把他们送走，因为担心他们会发疯
and shipped them off for fear they'd gone mad.
你知道的
And you know it.
但我们就在这儿
But here we are.
我的儿子赢得了“顶级杀手”的称号
My son has won the title of Top Slayer.
没有人比他更惊讶...
No one is more surprised...
...或者比我更自豪
...or more proud than I am.
今天，我的儿子成为一名战士
Today, my boy becomes a warrior.
今天，他成为了我们中的一员！
Today, he becomes one of us!
是的！
Yeah!
嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
呃呃！呃呃！
Hiccup! Hiccup!
小心那条龙
Watch out for that dragon.
我担心的不是那条龙
It's not the dragon I'm worried about.
听着，我要试着结束这一切，
Look, I'm gonna try to put an end to all this,
但如果那里出了问题，那就……
but if something goes wrong in there, just...
不要参与
don't get involved.
我爸爸太尊重你了
My dad respects you too much.
是的
Yeah.
但...
But...
你有我没有的东西
you have something I don't.
这是我们谁都没有的东西
Something none of us have.
所以...我会支持你，
So... I'm going to stand by you,
无论发生什么
come what may.
Come what may.
是时候了，希卡普
It's time, Hiccup.
把他打死吧，儿子
Knock him dead, son.
嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
呃呃！呃呃！
Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
加油，希卡普！
Go, Hiccup!
把我教你的一切都展示给他们看！
Show 'em everything I taught you!
应该是我
Should've been me.
呼 还好吗？
Whew. All right?
人群很拥挤，不是吗？
Good crowd, isn't it?
呃呃！呃呃！
Hiccup! Hiccup!
嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！嗝！
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
我会用锤子
I would have gone with the hammer.
只是，只是给他一个机会
Just-just give him a chance.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
他在做什么？
What is he doing?
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不是他们中的一员
I'm not one of them.
—停止战斗 —不
-Stop the fight. -No.
你们都需要看看这个
You all need to see this.
它们并不是我们想象的那样
They're not what we think they are.
我们没必要杀死他们
We don't have to kill them.
我说了停止打架！
I said stop the fight!
走开！
Out of my way!
快离开那里，希卡普！
Get out of there, Hiccup!
呃呃！
Hiccup!
快，快！抓住他的手！
Quick, quick! Grab his hand!
—爬上来 —希卡普，抓住我的手！
-Climb up. -Hiccup, grab my hand!
—上来！—快点！
-Get up here! -Hurry up!
快过来！抓住他的手！
Get over here, man! Just grab his hand!
阿斯特丽德，回来！
Astrid, get back here!
这是命令！
That's an order!
跑步！
Run!
快点
Come on.
呃呃！
Hiccup!
夜煞
Night Fury.
—夜煞！—他是真实存在的！
-Night Fury! -He's real!
好的，伙计 继续吧 走吧
All right, bud. Go on. Go.
快，快！到他身边去！
Go, go! Get to the side of him!
走开，希卡普！
Get out of the way, Hiccup!
不，停下来 你只会让事情变得更糟！
No, stop. You're only making it worse!
阿斯特丽德！
Astrid!
我知道了 走吧！
I got it. Go!
斯托伊克，他不会伤害你的
Stoick, he won't hurt you.
不！
No!
无牙！
Toothless!
不
Don't.
把它拿下来！
Take it down!
抓住它的腿！
Grab its legs!
—按住！—不！
-Hold it down! -No!
—不，别伤害他！—退后！
-No, don't hurt him! -Stay back!
你呢...
And you...
把它和其他的放在一起
Put it with the others.
—我早该知道的！—爸爸
-I should have known! -Dad.
—我应该看到这些迹象的 —爸爸！
-I should have seen the signs. -Dad!
我们达成协议了！
We had a deal!
我知道，但那是以前……
I-I know, but that was before...
一切都太混乱了
It's all so messed up.
那么，戒指里的一切，究竟是诡计？谎言？
So everything in the ring, what, a-a trick? A lie?
不，我早就应该告诉你
No, I-I should have told you before now.
把这事发泄在我身上吧……这是我的错……
Take that out on me... it's my fault...
但请不要伤害无牙仔
but please don't hurt Toothless.
龙？
The dragon?
这就是你所担心的吗？
That's what you're worried about?
不是那些你差点杀死的人吗？
Not the people you almost killed?
他不危险 他、他在保护我
He's not dangerous. He-he was protecting me.
老天爷啊，他们把你母亲带走了！
They took your mother, for gods' sake!
如果她能看到你现在和他们站在那里
If she could see you now standing there with them
他们已经杀害了我们数百人
when they've killed hundreds of us.
我们已经杀死了数千只！
And we've killed thousands of them!
他们为自己辩护
They defend themselves.
就这样
That's all.
他们袭击我们是因为他们不得不这么做
They raid us because they have to.
如果他们没有带回足够的食物，
If they don't bring enough food back,
它们自己也会被吃掉
they'll be eaten themselves.
他们的岛上还有其他东西
There's something else on their island.
我从未见过这样的龙
A dragon like I've never seen.
他们的岛屿？
Their island?
你已经去过巢穴了
You've been to the nest.
我说过巢穴吗？
Did I say nest?
你是怎么找到它的？
How did you find it?
我没有，无牙仔有
I didn't. Toothless did.
只有龙才能找到这个岛
Only a dragon can find the island.
不，爸爸，不
No. Dad, no.
你不知道自己面对的是什么
You don't know what you're up against.
这和你以前见过的完全不一样
This is nothing like you've ever seen.
你不可能赢得这场胜利
You can't win this one.
在你的一生中，你能不能
For once in your life, would you please
听我说完？
just listen to me?
你已经把你的命运和他们联系在一起了
You've thrown your lot in with them.
你不是我们中的一员
You're not one of us.
你不是我的儿子
You're not my son.
准备好船只！
Ready the ships!
黎明即起航！
We sail at dawn!
冲锋在前线！
Forward on the leading line!
稍微向外摆动
Swing it out slightly.
她来了 轻松
Here she comes. Easy.
小心头部
Careful with the head.
哦，现在要小心了
Oh, careful now.
武器已上膛！
Weapons loaded!
船上有备用索具吗？
Spare rigging aboard?
—是的 —扬帆起航！
-Aye. -Hoist the sails!
好的，酋长
Aye, Chief.
—准备好桨 —是的，斯托伊克
-Ready the oars. -Aye, Stoick.
我们启航前往冥界之门！
We set sail for Helheim's Gate!
带我们回家吧，魔鬼
Lead us home, devil.
我试图阻止他们
I tried to stop them.
我最终给了他们他们想要的东西
I ended up giving them exactly what they wanted.
我应该只是...
I should've just...
当我在树林里发现他时我就应该杀了他
I should've killed him when I found him in those woods.
这对于每个人来说都会更好
It would have been better for everyone.
是的
Yeah.
我们其他人也会这么做的
The rest of us would have done it.
那么，你为什么不这么做呢？
So, why didn't you?
—你为什么不呢？—我不知道
-Why didn't you? -I don't know.
—我不能 —这不是答案
-I-I couldn't. -That's not an answer.
为什么这对你来说突然变得如此重要？
Why is this so important to you all of a sudden?
因为我想记住你现在说的话
Because I want to remember what you say right now.
为了爱...因为我很软弱
For the love of... Because I was weak.
因为我是个懦夫，因为我不会
Because I was a coward, because I wouldn't
—杀死一条龙 —你当时说的是“不会”
-kill a dragon. -You said "wouldn't" that time.
随便！我不会！
Whatever! I wouldn't!
我是第一个维京人，谁知道多久了
I'm the first Viking in who knows how long
谁不会杀死一条龙呢？
who wouldn't kill a dragon.
不过，我是第一个骑的
First to ride one, though.
所以？
So?
我不会杀他因为......
I wouldn't kill him because...
......他看上去和我一样害怕
...he looked just as frightened as I was.
当我看着他时...
When I looked at him...
我看到了我自己
I saw myself.
我敢打赌他现在真的害怕了
Bet he's really frightened now.
你要做什么呢？
What are you gonna do about it?
出色地
Eh.
可能是做了一些愚蠢的事情
Probably something stupid.
唔
Hmm.
嗯，你已经这样做了
Well, you've already done that.
然后发生了一些疯狂的事情
Then something crazy.
这才像样
That's more like it.
表明你的立场
Sound your positions.
保持在听力范围内
Stay within earshot.
到船尾有一长度
One length to your stern.
在你的右舷
On your starboard flank.
他们为什么不进攻？
Why aren't they attacking?
也许他们知道一些我们不知道的事情
Maybe they know something we don't.
你只是一个自讨苦吃的人吗？
Are you just a glutton for punishment or what?
这次我们有机会奋起反抗
We have a fighting chance this time.
感谢 Hiccup
Thanks to Hiccup.
你认为我们还要多久...
How long do you think we're gonna...
嘘
Shh.
让开，德吕尔
Step aside, Drül.
— 把桨放上去！— 把桨放进去
-Ship the oars! -Oars in.
好的，等一下
Okay, wait.
你简直是在全村人面前丢脸
You just disgraced yourself in front of the whole village.
—我们为什么要听你的？—因为我这么说
-Why would we listen to you? -'Cause I said so.
没错 大家注意听
Exactly. Pay attention, gang.
听着，我爸爸的本意是好的，但他很固执
Look, my dad means well, but he's stubborn.
他即将陷入困境，
And he's about to be way in over his head,
所以这取决于我们
so it's up to us.
我们？
Us?
如果没有你们，我不可能完成这个任务
I can't pull this off without you guys.
你们每个人都有自己独特的才华
And you all have something special to offer.
别再说了
Say no more.
你很明智地寻找了世界上最致命的武器
You were wise to seek the world's most deadly weapon.
这就是我
It's me.
你有狂野的一面，我喜欢这一点
You've got a wild side, and I like it.
阿斯特丽德，你是我们最强大的战士
Astrid, you're our strongest fighter.
我们需要你来领导我们
We need you to lead us.
究竟带领我们去往何方？
Lead us where exactly?
他们乘坐我们所有的船离开了
They left with every ship we have.
跟着我
Stick with me.
哦
Oh.
事情就是这样发生的
That's where that went.
保持低调 做好准备
Stay low. Be ready.
我们到了
We're here.
不，嗯嗯
No, uh-uh.
希卡普，我……
Hiccup, I...
放松
Relax.
没关系
It's okay.
呃，你要去哪儿？
Uh, where are you going?
你需要一些东西来帮助你坚持下去
You're gonna need something to help you hold on.
准备
Get ready.
这将是一个漫长的夜晚
It's gonna be a long night.
组成防线
Form a defensive line.
磨快斧头，小伙子们！
Sharpen those axes, lads!
首席
Chief.
准备好了，酋长
Ready, Chief.
—坚强起来 —是的，斯托伊克
-Stand strong. -Aye, Stoick.
—让你的人民感到骄傲 —我们会的，斯托伊克
-Make your people proud. -We will, Stoick.
今天我们摧毁
Today, we destroy
一劳永逸地结束龙的统治
the reign of the dragon once and for all.
不管怎样，它就在这里结束，就在此刻！
However this ends, it ends right here, right now!
所以让我们把这些魔鬼送回地狱吧！
So let's send these devils back to hell!
就这样吗？
Is that it?
这个窝是我们的！
The nest is ours!
这还没有结束
This isn't over.
弄清楚！
Get clear!
倒退！
Fall back!
撤退！全体撤退！
Fall back! Everyone, fall back!
撤退！
Retreat!
移动！
Move!
赶快上船！
Get to the ships!
不！
No!
到达岛的另一边
Get to the far side of the island.
好的，酋长 我们出发吧！
Aye, Chief. Let's move!
这边走！大家！
This way! All of you!
—伙计们，离开这里！—跟我来！
-Get out of here, lads! -Follow me!
戈伯，和其他人一起去
Gobber, go with the others.
怎么了？你要去哪儿？
Why? Where are you going?
事实上，我会留下来
Actually, I'm gonna stick around.
你的眼神充满狂野
You've got that wild look in your eye.
如果我把那东西给她们，她们就能得到一些时间
I can buy them some time if I give that thing
猎取一些东西
something to hunt.
我可以将这个时间加倍
And I can double that time.
我知道 我是个心软的人
I know. I'm a big softy.
你身上最柔软的部分是你的牙齿
Softest part of you is your teeth.
记住，那是他们的女王
Remember, that thing is their queen.
他们倾向于按照指示去做
They're inclined to do whatever it says.
我们必须帮助他们反击
We've got to help them fight back.
鱼腿，我们得到了什么？
Fishlegs, what do we got?
哦，呃，重装甲的头骨和尾巴，
Ooh, uh, heavily armored skull and tail,
非常适合打击和粉碎
perfect for bashing and crushing.
眼睛小，鼻孔大
Small eyes, large nostrils.
依靠听觉和嗅觉
Relies on hearing and smell.
—知道了，阿斯特丽德 —好的
-Got it. Astrid. -Okay.
鼻涕粗、鱼脚司，悬挂在它的盲点处
Snotlout, Fishlegs, hang in its blind spot.
制造一些噪音，让它保持混乱
Make some noise. Keep it confused.
拉夫，塔夫，找出它的射击极限
Ruff, Tuff, figure out its shot limit.
让它疯狂
Make it mad.
这是我们的特色！
That's our specialty!
大家尽量不要被杀死！
Try not to get killed, guys!
呃，这东西没有盲点
Uh, this thing doesn't have a blind spot.
那里！
There!
嘿，出价
Hey, bud.
我很好
I'm good.
当心
Be careful.
我知道，我知道，但是我，呃......我现在在这里
I know, I know, but I'm, uh... I'm here now.
继续敲击！
Keep hammering!
但我们却混淆了自己的龙！
But we're confusing our own dragons!
噢，不！
Oh, no!
这边走！
This way!
这边走！快点！快点！
This way! Come on! Come on!
伙计们，继续前进！继续前进！加油！
Guys, keep moving! Keep moving! Come on!
去！
Go!
那是我的孩子吗？
Is that my kid?
—鼻涕虫！—来吧！扔！
-Snotlout! -Come on! Throw it!
哇哦，姑娘
Whoa, girl.
正在下降
Going down.
我没事
I'm okay.
少一点就好
Less okay.
我抓到你了，鱼脚司
I got you, Fishlegs.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你的眼睛里进东西了吗？
Got something in your eye?
是啊！这可是顶级杀手啊
Yeah! Now, that's a Top Slayer.
你明白了，伙计
You got it, bud.
呃呃
Hiccup.
我只是想保护你
I was only trying to protect you.
我知道，爸爸
I know, Dad.
让我来回报你吧
Let me return the favor.
无论那里发生什么，
Whatever happens up there,
我很自豪地称你为我的儿子
I'm proud to call you my son.
这就是我所需要的
And that's all I need.
我们走吧
Let's go.
他醒了！
He's up!
你们两个，去抓 Snotlout
You two, get Snotlout.
我会分散女王的注意力
I'll distract the queen.
没错 看着我
That's right. Eyes on me.
鼻涕虫！
Snotlout!
现在！
Now!
噢，你一定是在跟我开玩笑
Oh, you have got to be kidding me.
哇哦！
Whoa!
我简直不敢相信这真的有效
I can't believe that worked.
是的
Yeah.
不，不，不，姑娘
No, no, no, girl.
反抗！别听她的！
Fight it! Don't listen to her!
甩掉它！
Shake it off!
阿斯特丽德
Astrid.
你抓到她了吗？
Did you get her?
去
Go.
那东西有翅膀
That thing has wings.
让我们看看它是否可以使用它们
Let's see if it can use them.
您认为这样就行了吗？
You think that did it?
是的
Yep.
好了，伙计，该消失了
All right, bud. It's time to disappear.
来了！
Here it comes!
你真是一个出色的领袖
Quite the chief you have in the making there.
机会
Aye.
小心！
Watch out!
好的，时间到了
Okay, time's up.
让我们看看这是否有效
Let's see if this works.
这就是你所拥有的一切吗？
Is that all you've got?
跟我在一起吧，伙计！
Stay with me, bud!
再等一会儿！
Just a little bit longer!
坚持住，无牙仔！
Hold, Toothless!
现在！
Now!
是的，伙计，我们......不！
Yeah, bud, we... No!
呃呃！
Hiccup!
呃呃？
Hiccup?
儿子？
Son?
呃呃！
Hiccup!
噢，他的
Oh, son.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
呃呃
Hiccup.
他还活着 他还活着！
He's alive. He's alive!
是的！
Yeah!
Yes!
谢谢...
Thank you...
...为了救我的儿子
...for saving my son.
嗯，你知道……他的大部分情况
Well, you know... most of him.
嘿，无牙仔
Hey, Toothless.
好的
Okay.
我在我的家里
I'm in my house.
你，你在我家
You-You're in my house.
我爸爸知道你在这里吗？
D-Does my dad know you're here?
哦，来吧
Oh, come on.
谢谢，伙计
Thanks, bud.
好的，我们开始吧
Okay, here we go.
无牙仔，留下来
Toothless, stay.
嘿，嘿，嘿！你不是应该去睡觉吗？
Hey, hey, hey! Shouldn't you be in bed?
好的 大家抓紧了
Okay. Hold on tight, guys.
开始了
Here we go.
哇哦，哇哦！
Whoa, whoa!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
就这样！
There you go!
—他在那儿！哦，哦 —哦！好的
-There he is! Oh, oh. -Oh! Okay.
那么，您觉得怎么样？
So, what do you think?
自从你离开后，发生了一些变化
A few changes since you've been out.
我告诉你，飞回这里真是一次相当不错的经历
Flying back here was, uh, quite an experience, let me tell you.
等等，等等，你……你骑着龙？
Wait, wait, you... you rode a dragon?
嗯...嗯，那只怪物被烧死了
Well... well, that monster burned
我们所有的船，所以我们并没有
all of our ships, so we didn't really
— 有很多... — 打嗝！
-have much of a... -Hiccup!
哦，不
Oh, no.
这次我做了什么？
What'd I do this time?
哎哟！
Ow!
那是为了吓唬我
That's for scaring me.
好吧，会一直这样吗？因为……
Okay, is it always gonna be like this? 'Cause...
其他一切都如此
And that's for everything else.
你知道，因为......因为我......我可以习惯这一点
You know, 'cause... 'cause I... I-I could get used to that.
是的
Yep.
事实证明，我们所需要的只是多一点这样的事
Turns out all we needed was a little more of this.
你刚才向我所有人做了手势
You just gestured to all of me.
嗯，你们大多数人都知道
Well, you know, most of you.
新的腿是我亲手做的，只需轻轻一划
New leg is my handiwork with just a dash
充分展现你的古怪天赋
of your kooky flair thrown in for good measure.
开始了
Here we go.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
—你重建了它？—是的
-You rebuilt it? -Yeah.
我找到了你的设计
I found your designs.
还不错
Not too bad.
夜煞！
Night Fury!
—他在这儿 —怎么了？
-Here he is. -What is it?
那是什么啊？
What is it, huh?
想尝试一下吗？
Want to take it for a spin?
这是伯克
This is Berk.
搬到这里来你一定是疯了
You'd have to be crazy to move here.
留下来就更疯狂了
Even crazier to stay.
这不适合胆小的人
It's not for the faint of heart.
哇喔！
Whoo!
任何生长在这里的食物
Any food that grows here
又硬又没味
is tough and tasteless.
快点！
Come on!
在这里成长的人们……
The people that grow here...
-哇哦！-...甚至更是如此
-Whoa! -...are even more so.
唯一的好处就是有宠物
The only upsides are the pets.
而其他地方可能有小马或小狗……
While other places may have ponies or puppies...
—来吧，伙计 —……我们有……
-Come on, bud. -...we have...
...龙
...dragons.
MODIS译制字幕组
♪ 运气真好，她对我如此眷顾 ♪
♪ Luck, how she favors me ♪
♪ 穿越冰冷而狂风暴雨的大海 ♪
♪ Through cold and stormy seas ♪
♪ 到达如此奇妙的景象 ♪
♪ To reach such wond'rous sights ♪
♪ 我总是向前走 ♪
♪ I travel always forward ♪
♪ 嗬，巨龙嬉戏的地方 ♪
♪ Ho, where the dragons play ♪
♪ 我们不会有危险 ♪
♪ No harm shall come our way ♪
♪ 我们又要启航一天 ♪
♪ We sail for another day ♪
♪ 一路走好，你就是我的归途 ♪
♪ Fare thee well, you are my homeward ♪
♪ 爱你，永远都在 ♪
♪ Love, you shall always be ♪
♪ 充满爱意的臂膀 ♪
♪ The loving arms for me ♪
♪ 没有宝藏可以比拟 ♪
♪ No treasure can compare ♪
♪ 没有什么困难能让我动摇 ♪
♪ No hardships make me falter yet ♪
♪ 不要流泪 ♪
♪ Do not shed a tear ♪
♪ 亲爱的，请与我告别 ♪
♪ Bid me farewell, my dear ♪
♪ 别害怕，我的心就在这里 ♪
♪ Fear not for my heart lies here ♪
♪ 我回来，因为你是我的归宿 ♪
♪ I return for you are my homeward ♪
♪ 你带我回家 ♪
♪ You are bringing me homeward ♪
♪ 你要带我回家 ♪
♪ You are bringing me home. ♪
♪ 爱 ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ 你永远是 ♪
♪ You shall always be ♪
♪ 充满爱意的臂膀 ♪
♪ The loving arms for me ♪
♪ 没有宝藏可以比拟 ♪
♪ No treasure can compare ♪
♪ 没有困难 ♪
♪ No hardships ♪
♪ 让我再动摇 ♪
♪ Make me falter yet ♪
♪ 不要流泪 ♪
♪ Do not shed a tear ♪
♪ 亲爱的，请与我告别 ♪
♪ Bid me farewell, my dear ♪
♪ 不要害怕 ♪
♪ Fear not ♪
♪ 因为我的心在这里 ♪
♪ For my heart lies here ♪
♪ 我回来了 ♪
♪ I return ♪
♪ 因为你是我的归宿 ♪
♪ For you are my homeward ♪
♪ 你带我来 ♪
♪ You are bringing me ♪
♪ 回家 ♪
♪ Homeward. ♪